http://www.chinooksailing.com/pages/privacy-policy

Menu
My Cart: (0)
Home
»
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Your privacy is important to us at Chinook Sailing Products. We understand that you provide private information in the course of doing business with us online, by mail and by telephone. So that you understand how we operate to protect this information, the following is a description of our policies on collecting and protecting the information you provide to us. Other information related to the terms of use of this Website are also provided.
Your Personal Information
Personal Information is gathered by Chinook Sailing Products for the sole benefit of Chinook Sailing Products. Chinook Sailing Products does not sell, rent or provide your "Personal Information" to third parties, except as described below. Personal Information as used herein refers to data and facts about you which include, but are not limited to, your name, age, address, email address, financial information (account or credit card numbers),  phone number, etc. Personal Information is personal to you in that it belongs to you and identifies who you are. There are a variety of pathways, electronic and otherwise, by which any single element of these data can point to you personally. Personal Information does NOT include your IP Address as defined below. Personal Information is generally kept for Chinook Sailing Products business which is primarily used to assist you in your current or future communications and/or transactions or in analyzing sales trends.
Personal Information is primarily obtained from a form required to be completed when customers request information, products or services, including subscribing to our email list.   Personal Information that is collected by Chinook Sailing Products is used to bill the user for products and services, and to ship those products. Personal Information is used to send orders, information about our company, and promotional material to our customers. Personal Information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings by following the directions in those mailings.
Chinook Sailing Products may use online surveys which ask visitors for Personal Information which usually includes contact information (typically the customer's email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We would potentially use Personal Information gathered from such surveys to send the user promotional material from Chinook Sailing Products.  Chinook Sailing Products may also run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for selected Personal Information such as contact information (typically the customer's email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We would potentially use Personal Information gathered from such contests to send users promotional material from Chinook Sailing Products. The customer's Personal Information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary (i.e. when someone wins a contest.). Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.
Cookies and IP Addresses
Chinook Sailing Products also collects, uses, and monetizes IP Addresses. An IP Address is a convention of the Internet Protocol that identifies your "virtual" address on the internet. This IP Address is not personal to you and does not identify any of your Personal Information. All devices connected to a network have an IP Address permitting communication to and from the device. If you connect to the Internet from your computer, then you have an IP Address that looks something like this: 207.16.154.100. In the simplest possible terms, your IP Address contains no data that identifies you as a person. It is only a logical address allowing you to connect to others and others to locate your computer. An IP Address can be used variously as set forth herein. We could potentially use an IP Address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. The IP Address may be used to help identify you and your shopping cart and to gather broad demographic information. Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. We may use cookies for other purposes such as site personalization as well. You can reject cookies and still use Chinook Sailing Products site, however, it will disable the ability for the site to recognize your cart, your account and any personalization efforts.
Chinook Sailing Products may monetize or otherwise provide anonymous IP Addresses to third parties. Chinook Sailing Products sometimes employs other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples of such may include hosting our website, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links, retargeted advertising, analyzing data, etc. These third parties have access only to IP Addresses; no Personal Information is provided to them.
External Links
This site may contain links to other sites. Chinook Sailing Products is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Websites.
Your Rights and Obligations With Respect To Content and Material Submitted by You
Any comments, reviews, posts, feedback, questions, answers, notes, messages, images, video, audio, materials, ideas, suggestions or other communications you submit to Chinook Sailing Products are not private or proprietary. By submitting User Content on or through Chinook Sailing Products, you grant Chinook Sailing Products an irrevocable, royalty-free, worldwide, perpetual right and license to use, copy, modify, display, archive, store, distribute, reproduce and create derivative works based upon such User Content, in any form, media, software or technology of any kind now existing or developed in the future. By submitting such User Content on or through Chinook Sailing Products, you are confirming that (a) you are the sole author of the User Content and the User Content originated with you and was not copied in whole or in part from any other work; (b) you have obtained all necessary permissions associated with the User Content, including without limitation permissions relating to copyrights, trademarks, rights of publicity and/or rights of privacy; (c) the User Content does not contain hate speech or profanity and is not libelous, obscene or otherwise in violation of this Agreement, and (d) that you are not a minor and have the legal right and capacity to enter into and comply with these Terms. By submitting any such User Content on or through Chinook Sailing Products, you grant Chinook Sailing Products permission to use your name, alias and any other information (as provided by you) to attribute such User Content to you. Without limiting the generality of the previous sentence, and subject to our Privacy Policy, you authorize Chinook Sailing Products and its affiliates to share the User Content across all affiliated Web sites, and to use your name and any other information in connection with its use of such User Content. You also grant Chinook Sailing Products and its affiliates the right to use any material, information, ideas, concepts, know-how or techniques contained in such User Content. We are not responsible for the similarity of any of our Content or programming in any media to User Content submitted by you. Any and all rights granted in this section are granted without the need for any compensation to you in any form. User Content does not reflect the views of Chinook Sailing Products, and Chinook Sailing Products does not represent or guarantee the truthfulness, accuracy, completeness, timeliness or reliability of any User Content, nor endorses or supports any opinions expressed in any User Content. In no event shall Chinook Sailing Products have or be construed to have any responsibility or liability for or in connection with any User Content. If we determine, in our sole discretion, you or any User Content you submit violates this Agreement, we reserve the right, at any time, without notice and without limiting any and all other rights we may have under this Agreement, to (a) refuse to allow you to submit further User Content, (b) remove and delete your User Content, (c) revoke your registration and right to use the User Content Submission Features and (d) use any technological, legal, operational or other means available to enforce the terms of this Agreement, including, without limitation, blocking specific IP addresses or deactivating your registration, access using your e-mail address, your user name and password.
CHINOOK SAILING PRODUCTS DOES NOT ENDORSE THE USER CONTENT, IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE USER CONTENT AND SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY RESPONSIBILITY OR LIABILITY TO ANY PERSON OR ENTITY (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, PERSONS WHO MAY USE OR RELY ON SUCH USER CONTENT) FOR ANY LOSS, DAMAGE (WHETHER ACTUAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, PUNITIVE OR OTHERWISE), INJURY, CLAIM, LIABILITY OR OTHER CAUSE OF ANY KIND OR CHARACTER BASED UPON OR RESULTING FROM ANY USER CONTENT PROVIDED THROUGH THIS WEB SITE.
How Secure Is Information About Me?
We work to protect the security of your Personal Information during any transmission of same by using software which encrypts information you input.
We do not reveal the entirety of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing.
It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer.
Opting Out Of Communications From CHINOOK SAILING PRODUCTS
You may elect not to receive on-line or off-line communication from us. To stop receiving Chinook Sailing Products email or catalogs, manage your email settings in My Account.
Changes to Our Privacy Policy
Chinook Sailing Products will potentially update this privacy policy from time to time. We will contact anyone on our email list when there are fundamental changes that will possibly affect the way you interact with us.
How to Contact chinook sailing products
If you have any questions or concerns about privacy, please feel free to contact us. To do so you can send an email to info@chinooksailing.com You can contact us by regular mail at:
Chinook Sailing Products You can call us at (541) 374-5005.
This privacy policy sets out how {{config path="general/store_information/name"}} uses and protects any information that you give {{config path="general/store_information/name"}} when you use this website. {{config path="general/store_information/name"}} is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. {{config path="general/store_information/name"}} may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
name
contact information including email address
demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers
For the exhaustive list of cookies we collect see the List of cookies we collect section.
What we do with the information we gather
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
Internal record keeping.
We may use the information to improve our products and services.
We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at {{config path="trans_email/ident_general/email"}}
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to {{config path="general/store_information/address"}}.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
List of cookies we collect
The table below lists the cookies we collect and what information they store.
COOKIE name
COOKIE Description
CART
The association with your shopping cart.
CATEGORY_INFO
Stores the category info on the page, that allows to display pages more quickly.
COMPARE
The items that you have in the Compare Products list.
CURRENCY
Your preferred currency
CUSTOMER
An encrypted version of your customer id with the store.
CUSTOMER_AUTH
An indicator if you are currently logged into the store.
CUSTOMER_INFO
An encrypted version of the customer group you belong to.
CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS
Stores the Customer Segment ID
EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE
A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled or not.
FRONTEND
You sesssion ID on the server.
GUEST-VIEW
Allows guests to edit their orders.
LAST_CATEGORY
The last category you visited.
LAST_PRODUCT
The most recent product you have viewed.
NEWMESSAGE
Indicates whether a new message has been received.
NO_CACHE
Indicates whether it is allowed to use cache.
PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART
A link to information about your cart and viewing history if you have asked the site.
POLL
The ID of any polls you have recently voted in.
POLLN
Information on what polls you have voted on.
RECENTLYCOMPARED
The items that you have recently compared.
STF
Information on products you have emailed to friends.
STORE
The store view or language you have selected.
USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE
Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.
VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS
The products that you have recently viewed.
WISHLIST
An encrypted list of products added to your Wishlist.
WISHLIST_CNT
The number of items in your Wishlist.
Copyright © 2020 Chinook Sailing Products • Shopify Theme by Underground • Powered by Shopify
